∮ 没有什么可以捆绑你的双手 ∮
∮ There'll be no strings to bind your hands ∮
∮ 除非我的爱不让你的心迷失 ∮
∮ Not if my love can't bind your heart ∮
∮ 本来就没有必要再反对什么 ∮
∮ There's no need to take a stand ∮
∮ 早先我就不应该开始这一切 ∮
∮ For it was I who chose to start ∮
∮ 如果清晨预示了我们的罪恶 ∮
∮ If morning's echoes say we've sinned ∮
∮ 也许这就是我一直想要的 ∮
∮ Well, it was what I wanted now ∮
∮ 如果我们是暗夜的受害者 ∮
∮ And if we're victims of the night ∮
∮ 我将不会在光明里迷失 ∮
∮ I won't be blinded by the light ∮
∮ 叫我一声晨间天使 天使 ∮
∮ Just call me angel of the morning angel ∮
∮ 在你离去时抚摸一下我的脸颊 ∮
∮ Just touch my cheek before you leave me, baby ∮
∮ 叫我一声晨间天使 天使 ∮
∮ Just call me angel of the morning angel ∮
∮ 在你离去时抚摸一下我的脸颊 ∮
∮ Just touch my cheek before you leave me, baby ∮
∮ 叫我一声晨间天使 天使 ∮
∮ Just call me angel of the morning angel ∮
∮ 在你离去时抚摸一下我的脸颊 ∮
∮ Just touch my cheek before you leave me, darling ∮
∮ 叫我一声晨间天使 天使 ∮
∮ Just call me angel of the morning angel ∮
∮ 在你离去时抚摸一下我的脸颊 ∮
∮ Just touch my cheek before you leave me, darling ∮
（嗨 我是死侍）
（惊悚赛格威之旅）
我在后面好孤单啊
Kinda lonesome back here.
帮我一下
Yeah, little help.
我得握好方向盘
Okay, um, just, I have to keep my hands on the wheel.
不好意思啦
Excuse me. Whoo!
我叫多芬德
Ah, Dopinder.
侍 死
Pool. Dead.
不错啊
Hmm, nice.
（水仙 白日梦空气清新剂）
味道不错吧？
Smells good, no?
我不是说清新剂 说那妹子呢
Not the Daffodil Daydream. The girl.
是吧 吉塔
Ah, yes. Gita.
她挺漂亮的吧
Hmm. She is quite lovely.
她本来可能成为我称心的老婆
She would have made me a very agreeable wife.
但…
But, um…
吉塔的心被我表哥班都偷走了
Gita's heart has been stolen by my cousin Bandhu.
他这个人啊 又迷人 又不老实
He is as dishonorable as he is attractive.
多芬德 我开始觉得
Dopinder, I'm starting to think
今天我上你这车 肯定是有理由的
there's a reason I'm in this cab today.
是啊 先生 我这车不是你叫的吗？
Yeah, sir, you called for it, remember?
不 这位棕皮肤瘦身板朋友 爱…
No, my slender brown friend. Love…
是个非常美妙的事情
is a beautiful thing.
遇见爱时 全世界都会飘着水仙花的香味
When you find it, the whole world tastes like Daffodil Daydream.
所以你要把握爱…
So you gotta hold onto love…
- 紧紧把握 - 啊
- tight! - Ah!
千万不要放手
And never let go.
不要重蹈我的覆辙
Don't make the same mistakes I did.
- 明白没？- 明白了
- Got it? - Yeah.
不然全世界的味道 闻着就像刚做完高温瑜珈的琼肥妈
Or else the whole world tastes like Mama June after hot yoga.
先生 琼肥妈是什么味道？
Sir, what does Miss Mama June taste like?
- 就像俩流浪汉穿着灌满尿的鞋在滚床单 - 好了 够了
- Like two hobos fucking in a shoe filled with piss. - Okay, enough.
我能说上一天 多芬德 重点是 这很糟
I can go all day, Dopinder. The point is, it's bad!
是很糟
Hmm, it's bad.
死侍先生 你为什么要穿成这样？
Uh, why the fancy red suit, Mr. Pool?
因为今天是圣诞节 多芬德
Oh, that's because it's Christmas Day, Dopinder.
而且我在追我淘气榜单上一个人
And I'm after someone on my naughty list.
我已经等了一年零三周…
I've been waiting one year, three weeks…
零六天…
six days and, oh…
零14分钟 就为了让他 为他对我做过的事付出代价
14 minutes to make him fix what he did to me.
他对你做过什么 死侍先生？
And what did he do to you, Mr. Pool?
给你看…
This Shit…
嘭
Boo!
它们不会让你失望的
They won't disappoint.
最好不会
They'd better not.
下个月的货运呢？
And what about next month's shipment?
不会再有了
There won't be one.
又不是只有你要打仗
You're not the only one with a war to win.
不行
That won't do.
既然我们在供应上面有这么点小问题…
See, we've had this small disruption to our supply chain…
就需要你有点耐心
We'd appreciate your patience.
可以
Okay.
下个月我们会全数运来
We'll deliver in full the following month.
和你做生意很开心
Pleasure doing business with you.
该死的变种人
Fucking mutant.
该死
Oh, shit!
我把我的弹药包给忘了
I forgot my ammo bag.
- 我们要折回去吗？- 不用了 没时间了
- Shall we turn back? - No, no time.
妈的 我还有这个
Fuck it. I got this.
9 10 11 12颗子弹 要么完蛋
9, 10, 11, 12 bullets, or bust.
停车
Right here!
一共27.5美元
That's, uh, $27.50.
我工作时从不带钱包
I… I never carry a wallet when I'm working.
会破坏我这身战服的线条美
Ruins the lines of my suit.
- 噢 - 但是… 呃
- Oh. - But, uh,
不如我们爽快地击个掌？
how about a crisp high five?
好吧
Okay.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
也祝您四月周二快乐 死侍
And a convivial Tuesday in April to you too, Pool!
∮ 嘿耶 我今晚想咻咻咻 ∮
∮ Hey, yeah I wanna shoop, baby ∮
∮ 咻 咻 呗 ∮
∮ Shoop shooop ba-doop, shoop ba-doop ∮
∮ Shoop ba-doop, ba-doop, ba-doop ∮
∮ 你拿着枪 身材匀称 尤其是背影 ∮
∮ You're packed and you're stacked 'specially in the back ∮
∮ 兄弟 想谢谢你老妈给了你个翘臀 ∮
∮ Brother, wanna thank your mother for a butt like that ∮
∮ 能让我摸一摸那摇摆的大波吗？ ∮
∮ Can I get some fries with that shake-shake boobie? ∮
∮ 要是眼神也能像枪一样杀死你 ∮
∮ If looks could kill you would be an uzi ∮
∮ 你就是只小猎枪 砰 ∮
∮ You're a shotgun, bang! ∮
哇… 哦
Wha… Oh!
你好啊 我知道 好吗？
Oh, hello. I know, right?
我得去跪舔谁
Whose balls did I have to fondle
才能拍到我的第一部专属电影？
to get my very own movie?
我可不能告诉你
I can't tell you,
不过那人名字里确实有个「金刚」哦
but it does rhyme with "Polverine."
我跟你说
And let me tell you,
他下面那玩意儿可真不错
he's got a nice pair of smooth criminals down under.
总之 我还有事 去整一下脸 还有…
Anyway, I got places to be, a face to fix and, oh…
要杀的坏人
Bad guys to kill.
全力出击
Maximum effort.
老二暴击
Cock shot.
哈…
Ha!
好奢华的真皮座椅
Rich Corinthian leather.
我要找弗朗西斯
I'm looking for Francis!
你见过这人吗？
Have you seen this man?
噢…
Ow. Ow. Ow. Ow.
Ow. Ow!
哟吼 哟吼
Yanky, yanky!
虽然我从没这么说过 但是别吞哦
I've never said this, but don't swallow.
该死
Shit.
我是不是没关炉子？
Did I leave the stove on?
现在播报突发新闻
Now, breaking news.
今晨于跨城高速上
A multi-car collision turned shots fired
一起多辆汽车相撞事故中出现多发枪击
on the crosstown expressway this morning.
由于交通堵塞 警察未能赶到现场
Gridlock has kept police from the scene.
建议市民避免出门
Residents are advised to remain in their homes.
持械攻击者非常危险 并身着…
The assailant appears to be armed, dangerous, and wearing…
- 一套红衣 - 一套红衣
- a red suit. - A red suit.
死侍
Deadpool.
黑后 走 我们有任务了
Negasonic! Come, we have mission.
钢力士 等等
Colossus, wait up.
我给了死侍那么多机会 让他加入我们
I've given Deadpool every chance to join us…
但他就跟个孩子似的
but he'd rather act like a child.
还是个全副武装的孩子
A heavily-armed child.
他什么时候才能成熟点 能看到成为X战警一员的好处？
When will he grow up and see benefits of becoming X-Man?
什么好处？合身的紧身衣？
Which benefits? The matching unitards?
每隔几年就会爆炸的房子？
The house that blows up every few years?
拜托
Please.
历经磨难才能得到历练
House blowing up builds character.
你吃过早饭了吧？
You ate breakfast, yes?
早饭是一天中最重要的一餐了
Breakfast is most important meal of day.
给你 蛋白棒 对骨骼好
Here, protein bar. Good for bones.
死侍说不定想打断你的骨头
Deadpool may try to break yours.
让开
Get out of the way!
嘿
Hey! Whoo!
等等
Wait!
你们可能想知道 「为什么要穿红衣服？」
You may be wondering, "Why the red suit?"
因为这样坏人就看不出我流血了
Well, that's so bad guys can't see me bleed.
这位也有同样的想法呢
This guy's got the right idea.
他穿的是红棕色的裤子
He wore the brown pants.
好吧 我只有12颗子弹…
Fine! I only have 12 bullets…
所以你们要共同享用
so you're gonna have to share!
开始倒数吧
Let's count them down.
该死
Shit.
去你的
Motherfucker!
十 该死的
10! Shit!
九 操
Nine. Fuck.
八
Eight.
该死
Shit-fuck!
差死侍
Bad Deadpool.
七 好死侍
Seven. Good Deadpool.
有人没数好哦 六
Someone's not counting. Six.
四
Four…
打到你啦
Gotcha.
直接打中菊花了
Right up main street.
三 二
Three, two!
太蠢了 值
Stupid! Worth it.
啊
Ah!
今晚我要好好撸一发
I'm touching myself tonight.
弗朗西斯
Francis!
弗朗西斯…
Francis…
搞什么鬼
What the shit-biscuit!
你在哪啊 弗朗西斯？
Where you at, Francis?
你又不是弗朗西斯
You're not Francis.
玩儿真的？袖子都卷起来了？
Really? Rolling up the sleeves?
你可能在想
You're probably thinking,
「我男朋友说过这是部超级英雄片…
"My boyfriend said this was a superhero movie…
但那个穿红衣服的人
but that guy in the red suit just turned
直接把另一个人做成肉串啦「
that other guy into a fucking kabab!"
好吧 我可能很「超级」 但可不是英雄
Well, I may be super, but I'm no hero.
而且 没错 严格来说 这是谋杀
And yeah, technically, this is a murder.
但有些特别美好的爱情故事 就是从谋杀开始的
But some of the best love stories start with a murder.
这就确确实实是一个爱情故事
And that's exactly what this is, a love story.
为了说清楚点
And to tell it right…
我得带你回到
I gotta take you back to long before
我穿这身红色弹力衣之前
I squeezed this ass into red spandex.
（两年前）
我说慢点行吗
Look, would it help if I slow it down for you?
我没有叫披萨
I didn't order the pizza.
这是红礁路7348号码？你是梅山特先生吗？
Is this 7348 Red Ledge Drive? Are you Mr. Merchant?
是啊 可是我这位梅山特先生 没叫什么鬼披萨
Yeah, the Mr. Merchant who didn't order the fucking pie!
那是谁叫的？
Then who placed the call?
我
I did!
菠萝橄榄披萨是吗？
Pineapple and olive?
甜咸口味的
Sweet and salty.
你是谁？
The fuck are you?
你在我家干什…
The fuck you doing in my crib…
外皮烤焦了吗？
Is it burnt crust?
老天 但愿没有
I… God, I hope not. Um…
天呐 听我说 要是和那局扑克有关
Whoa… Man, look, if this is about that poker game.
我跟豪威说过 我跟他说…
I told Howie, I told him that…
好吧 你想要什么都拿去
Okay, uh, look, just take whatever you want.
谢了
Thanks.
先生 你对他下手之前
Sir, before you do anything to him,
介意先给我点小费吗？
do you mind if I get a big tip?
你叫杰里米是吧？
Uh, Jeremy, is it?
我叫韦德 韦德威尔逊
Umm-hmm. Wade. Wade Wilson.
小费是不可能的 杰儿
That is a no go on the tiperoo, Jer.
我不是来找他的
I'm not here for him.
是来找你的
I'm here for you.
哦
Oh.
哟 哇 差点儿就碰别人的枪头了
Okay, wow, dodged a big-time bullet on that one.
跟你还没完事呢
Not out of the woods yet.
少戴些花里胡哨的玩意儿
You need to seriously ease up on the bedazzling.
你身上那是衣服 不是吊灯
They're jeans, not a chandelier.
顺便说一句 钱包不还给你了 是你自己给我的
P.S. I'm keeping your wallet. You did kinda give it to me.
好吧 那个 兄弟 能把山姆的会员卡还给我…
Okay, just look, man, can I have my Sam's card…
再唧歪老子毙了你的猫
I will shoot your fucking cat!
我不知道这话是什么意思 我没养猫啊
I don't really know what that means. I don't have a cat.
那我刚刚拉屎的猫砂是谁的？
Then whose kitty litter did I just shit in?
管他呢 你告诉我
Anyhoo, tell me something…
什么情况是披萨无法改善的？
what situation isn't improved by pizza?
你是不是恰好认识梅根奥夫洛斯基？
Do you happen to know a Meghan Orflosky?
我说对了吗？奥夫洛斯基？
Getting that right? Orflosky?
- 奥洛夫斯基？好 - 对
- Orlovsky? Good. - Yeah?
因为她认识你
Because she knows you.
杰里米 我是
Jeremy, I belong to a group of guys
专门拿钱帮人揍人的
who take a dime to beat a fella down.
而小梅根呢 她没什么钱
And little Meghan, she's not made of money,
但她幸运得很
but lucky for her…
我也会心软
I got a soft spot.
- 可我… - 跟踪她
- But I'm a… - A stalker.
恐吓也会伤人的 杰儿
Threats hurt, Jer.
不过也完全比不上锯齿刀伤人
Though not nearly as badly as serrated steel.
所以离梅根远点
So keep away from Meghan.
知道了吗？
Cool?
是 先生
Yes, sir.
那这事儿就结了
Then we're done.
等等 结了？
Wait. We are?
是啊 就这么结了
Yeah. We're totally done.
你真该看看自己那副表情
You should've seen your face.
我不知道该做什么 我吓到了
I didn't know what to do. I was so scared.
我会心软的 记得吗？
Soft spot, remember?
你要是再敢瞟她一眼
You even look in her general direction again…
我都会让你好好看看
and you will learn in the worst of ways
我硬起来是什么样子
that I have some hard spots too.
我这话有歧义吧
That came out wrong.
有吗？
Or did it?
梅根？
Mmm… Meghan?
（披萨 菲戈餐厅）
（对不起）
这是杰里米留给你的最后的话 他说对不起
You've heard the last of Jeremy. He's sorry.
真的吗
No friggin' way.
真该把我的直排轮带来
Should've brought my roller blades.
给那些小毛头看看该怎么滑
Show these kids how it's done.
这也是种回报哈 但主要还是要给钱
Oh. And that's why we do it. But mostly the money.
嘿 你能去搞定我继父吗？
Hey, think you could fuck up my step-dad?
我弄的人都是活该
I give a guy a pavement facial, it's because he's earned it.
嘿 等等
Hey, wait!
你是我的英雄
You're my hero.
不不不不 我不是
No-no-no-no. That I ain't!
不是 永远不会是
Nope. Never will be.
去你妈的 韦德
Oh. Fuck you, Wade.
我是个坏人 收钱去教训更坏的人
I'm just a bad guy who gets paid to fuck up worse guys.
欢迎来到玛格丽特姐妹酒吧
Welcome to Sister Margaret's.
这里就好像我这种雇佣兵的人才市场
It's like a job fair for mercenaries.
就把我们看做混蛋牙仙吧
Think of us as really fucked up tooth fairies…
不同的是 牙仙收集落牙 留下钱 而我们敲掉牙齿 拿走钱
except we knock out the teeth and take the cash.
你最好祈祷 你的名字不会出现在我们的金卡片上
You'd best hope we never see your name on a gold card.
巴克 雷菲尔德…
Buck! Liefeld…
嘿 韦德
Hey, Wade!
韦德威尔逊 可怜人的守护圣人
Wade Wilson, patron saint of the pitiful.
需要什么？
What can I do for you?
要「吹箫」
I'd love a Blow Job.
哦 天呐 我也想要
Oh, God, me too.
我说的是酒 紧身裤男 不过首先…
The drink, moose knuckle. But first…
（杰里米盖瑞特）
嘿 我不会收人家的保姆钱 好吗？
Hey, and I ain't taking any babysitting money, all right?
记得把这些钱还给…
Make sure that gets back to Ms…
奥洛夫斯基
Orlovsky.
对 就是她
Yeah, her.
- 你确定？- 嗯
- You sure? - Hmm.
作为一个雇佣兵 你心肠还是很好的
You know, for a merc, you're pretty warm-blooded.
我打赌你也没拿那男孩怎么样
I bet you let the kid off easy, too.
他也不是个坏孩子 鼹鼠
Oh, he's not a bad kid, Weas.
就是稍稍跟踪了别人
Just a little light stalking.
我在他这个年纪 可比他坏多了
I was way worse than him when I was his age.
我去过国外各种地方…
I was traveling to exotic places…
巴格达 摩加迪沙 杰克逊维尔
Baghdad, Mogadishu, Jacksonville,
看见各种新奇的人 然后…
meeting new and exciting people. And then, uh…
杀了他们 是啊 我在你的Instagram上看到过
Killing them. Yeah, I've seen your Instagram.
那特种部队到底在杰克逊维尔干什么？
So what was Special Forces doing in Jacksonville, anyway?
那是机密
That's classified.
他们那有家特别赞的星期五餐厅
They have a wonderful TGI Fridays.
好吧 咖啡酒 奶酒加…
All right, Kahlua, Baileys and…
鲜奶油
whipped cream.
给你一杯「吹箫」
I give you a Blow Job.
你干嘛要我做这个？
Why do you make me make that?
凯莉 凯莉 凯莉…
Kelly, Kelly, Kelly…
把这个送给巴克
Take that over to Buck please,
告诉他是布思请他的 是个小前戏
and tell him it's from Boothe. Little foreplay.
你这么做有什么好处？
Remind me what good will come of this?
我不要 我只是骚扰他们
I don't take the shits. I just disturb them.
- 布思 - 噢
- Boothe! - Oh!
- 淡定 兄弟 - 等等 住手
- Easy, man. - Hold up! Hold up!
你想要怎样？
What you want?
- 干杯 祝你健康 - 干你的
- Cheers. To your health. - Fuck you.
过来 你个混蛋的
Come here, you fat fuck!
那是条新凳子
That's a new stool.
你他妈别给老子起来
Stay the fuck down.
哇 揍得屁滚尿流
Whoa! Took his ass out!
好的 让一让 让一让
All right, move. Move, move, move.
巴克 一边呆着去
Buck, go rest.
布思被揍了 然后倒下了
Boothe got hit then went down.
他还有呼吸
Yeah, he's still breathing.
今天没有赢家
Nobody wins today.
手段不错啊 韦德
Nice try, Wade.
真给你说准了 我押下一个死的是布思
You got me. I picked Boothe in the dead pool.
你押的谁？
Who did you pick?
嗯 韦德 这个嘛…
Yeah, Wade, about that, um…
不是吧
No.
你不会押我死吧
You did not bet on me to die.
（玛格丽特姐妹酒吧死亡赌局）
你押我死
You bet on me to die
去你的 真是世界上最糟糕的朋友
Motherfucker, you're the world's worst friend.
你想的美 我要活到102岁
Well, joke's on you. I'm living to 102.
再死掉 像底特律一样「长寿」
And then dying. Like the city of Detroit.
对不起 我只是… 我想赢钱
I'm sorry. I just… I wanted to win money.
我从没赢过什么
I never win anything.
管你呢
Whatever.
各位幸运兵 今天酒我请
Soldiers of fortune, drinks on me!
都是国内的酒 没有进口的
Domestic, nothing imported.
哇… 哇…
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa…
宝贝 你确定要倾情投入吗？
Baby, are you sure you wanna shoot your whole wad?
呃…
Uh…
衣服很紧啊
Tight.
- 瓦妮莎 - 韦德
- Vanessa. - Wade.
你这种女孩来这个地方来嘛？
What's a nice place like you doing in a girl like this?
这妹子我要
I'd hit that.
巴克 你最好道歉 省得…
Buck, you best apologize before…
对 受这个
Yeah, that.
快道歉 肥甘道夫
Say the magic words, Fat Gandalf.
- 抱歉 - 用鼻子呼吸
- I'm sorry. - Breathe through the nose.
我的脑子管不好我的…
I don't have a filter between my brain and my…
放手吧 行了 嘿…
Let go. Okay. Hey, oh, oh, oh…
- 放过他吧 他说过抱歉了 - 我是认真的
- Hakuna his tatas. He's sorry. - I'm working on it.
滚吧 快走 找个地儿施咒去
Get out of here. Go. Go cast a spell.
别碰这用来卖的身子
Hey. Hands off the merchandise.
用来卖？
Merchandise? Huh…
所以你是…
So you, uh…
跟人上床来挣钱的？
bump fuzzies for money?
- 是的 - 童年很不幸吧？
- Yep. - Rough childhood?
比你的不幸
Rougher than yours.
我出生前爸爸就走了
Daddy left before I was born.
我妈怀我前我爸就走了
Daddy left before I was conceived.
有被烟头烫过吗？
Ever had a cigarette put out on your skin?
不然烟头在哪灭？
Where else do you put one out?
我小时候被性侵过
I was molested.
我也有过 被我叔叔
Me too. Uncle.
被我好几位叔叔轮奸
Uncles. They took turns.
我自己的生日派对
I watched my own birthday party
都只能在上了锁的壁橱里透过锁眼看
through the keyhole of a locked closet…
那就是我的…
which also happens to be my…
卧室 真幸运 我睡在放洗碗机的纸盒里
Your bedroom. Lucky. I slept in a dishwasher box.
你家还有洗碗机呢
You had a dishwasher.
我都不知道睡觉是什么滋味
I didn't even know sleep.
基本上一天到晚都咬着情趣口塞
It was pretty much 24/7 ball gags,
被爆菊 被小丑上
brownie mix and clown porn.
谁会这么干？
Who would do such a thing?
希望是你 今晚晚些时候怎么样？
Hopefully you, later tonight?
嘿 我付你275美元加上…
Hey, what can I get for, uh, $275 and a…
一张优格冻酸奶店的积分卡怎么样？
a Yogurtland rewards card?
宝贝 给你大概48分钟 想怎么干就怎么干
Baby, about 48 minutes of whatever the fuck you want.
再加一杯低脂甜品
And a low-fat dessert.
她刚刚把一张礼品卡放到你嘴里了？
Did she just put a gift card in your mouth?
是时候让球进洞了
It's time to put balls in holes.
你说过我想怎么玩就怎么玩
You said whatever I want.
我明白
I get it.
你喜欢玩木滚球
You love skee ball.
兴趣比对滚床单要大得多
Apparently more than you love vagina.
好难选
That's a tough call.
我只是想认识认识真实的你
I just wanna get to know the real you, you know.
而不是好莱坞卖的那种
Not the short-shorted, two-dimensional
披着点衣服专门出来撩人的性格卡通形象
sex object peddled by Hollywood.
投球吧
Balls in holes.
投球
等着被打得落花流水吧
Prepare to lose tragically.
来啊 大个儿
Bring it, big man.
好嘞
Okay.
限量版…
The limited edition
《战神金刚》 请
Voltron: Defender of the Universe ring, por favor.
好嘞 来选一选
Okay. Here we go.
我想要这玩意儿想好久了
Had my eye on this sucker for a while.
我要这个橡皮擦
And I will take the pencil eraser.
好
Okay.
现在你是阿瑞斯星的守护者了
You are now the protector of the planet Arus.
而你可以擦掉
And you can erase stuff…
铅笔写下的东西
written in pencil.
女士？
M'lady?
我实在是不想告诉你
Well, I hate to break it to you…
可是48分钟到了
but your 48 minutes are up.
嘿 用这个指环能换几分钟？
Hey, how many more minutes can I get for this?
供你参考 五个迷你机器狮
FYI, five mini lion-bots come together
可以换一个超级机器人
to form one super-bot, so…
五个迷你机器狮？那就三分钟
Five mini lion-bots? Three minutes.
成交
Deal.
剩下2分钟37秒我们能做什么？
What do we do with the remaining two minutes, 37 seconds?
抱抱？
Cuddle?
你能坚持做多久？
How long can you keep this up?
一整年？
All year?
情人节快乐
Happy Valentine's Day.
春节快乐
Happy Chinese New Year.
狗年快乐
Year of the Dog.
放松
Relax.
妇女节快乐
And Happy International Women's Day.
不 不 不要
No. No. No.
大斋节快乐
Happy Lent.
- 韦德？- 抱歉
- Wade'? - Sorry.
万圣节快乐
Happy Halloween.
感恩节快乐
Happy Thanksgiving.
我爱你
I love you.
你的左腿是感恩节
If your left leg is Thanksgiving…
右腿是圣诞节
and your right leg is Christmas…
我可以在节日中间进去拜访你吗？
can I visit you between the holidays?
毛衣也太丑了
That sweater is terrible.
不过你穿红色很好看
But red looks good on you.
你穿红色很合适
Red's your color.
让你眼里的血丝更明显了
Brings out the bloodshot in your eyes.
听着 我最近在想…
Listen, I've been thinking…
认真的？
Really?
我们为什么那么合拍
about why we're so good together.
为什么？
Why's that?
你的疯狂和我的疯狂正好相配
Well, your crazy matches my crazy. Big time.
我们就像是两块拼图
And, uh, we're like two jigsaw pieces,
各自的形状都很奇怪
you know, the weird curvy edges…
但是拼在一起时 就是一幅完整的图画
You put them together and you can see the picture on top.
是啊
Right.
韦德…
Wade…
有件事我一直想问你
there's something I've been meaning to ask you.
不过只是因为你还没问我
But only because you haven't gotten around to asking me.
你愿意…
Will you, uh…
- 插到我的… - 嫁给我吗？
- stick it in my… - Marry me?
心有灵犀？
Uh… Jinx?
你藏在哪了？
Where were you hiding that?
没在哪
Nowhere.
这是我一个月的工资 所以…
They say one month's salary. So, uh…
你真想娶我？
You mean?
我愿意
I do.
那是我的台词
That's my line.
我爱你 韦德威尔逊
I love you, Wade Wilson.
你是要… 所以说…
You're supposed to… So that's a…
好
Yes! Whoo!
Yes!
我感觉自己就像个小姑娘似的
I feel just like a little girl.
我要是能一直抱着不放手多好啊？
What if I just held on and never let go?
就像大战快来了 尤达还骑在卢克背上一样
Just ride a bitch's back, like Yoda on Luke.
《星球大战》的笑话
Oh, Star Wars jokes.
是《帝国反击战》
Empire.
天呐
Jesus Christ.
你跟我真是天造地设
It's like I made you in a computer.
嘿
Hey.
完美
Perfect.
- 来看看 - 好嘞 去厕所
- Let's see. - All right, wee break.
甩一甩 对
Shake it, yeah.
是这样的
Here's the thing.
生活就是一系列的灾难…
Life is an endless series of train-wrecks…
时不时穿插进一小段快乐
with only brief, commercial-like breaks of happiness.
这就是最后的快乐时光了
This had been the ultimate commercial break.
也就是说
Which meant it was time to return
是时候回复正常了
to our regularly scheduled program.
搞什么…
What the…
哦 天呐 韦德？
Oh, my God. Wade?
你在开玩笑
You're clowning.
没在开玩笑？
You're not clowning?
我感觉你在开玩笑
I sense clowns.
人们对晚期癌症的诊断会有不同的反应
People react to news of late-stage cancer differently.
我们当然能看看多种选择
There are certainly options we can look into.
现在每天都有新药物被研制出
New drugs are being developed every day.
那我们要怎么办？
So what do we do?
肯定有办法
Surely there is something we can do.
我叔叔伊万就被诊断过患甲状腺癌
My uncle Ivan was diagnosed with thyroid cancer…
德国就有很多新的试验药物
and there were all these new experimental drugs from Germany.
瓦妮莎已经开始采取各种计划
Vanessa's already working on Plan A, B, all the way through Z.
我呢？我在记下她这张脸的所有细节
Me? I'm memorizing the details of her face.
就好像我第一次见她
Like it's the first time I'm seeing it.
或是最后一次
Or the last.
威尔逊先生
Mr. Wilson…
威尔逊先生？
Mr. Wilson?
慢慢消化一下
Take your time to process this.
别急于做任何决定 这很重要
It's important not to do anything rash.
如果我是一个90公斤重的
Now, if I were a 200-pound sack
叫弗朗西斯的混蛋 我会在哪？
of assholes named Francis, where would I hide?
观众此刻安静了下来
A hush falls over the crowd
因为天才新人韦德W威尔逊上场了
as rookie sensation Wade W. Wilson…
他来自加拿大萨斯喀彻温省里贾纳市 准备好要开动了
out of Regina, Saskatchewan, lines up the shot.
他的姿势不错
His form looks good.
所以里贾纳和「有意思」很押韵嘛
And that's why Regina rhymes with fun.
女士们先生们 你们所看到的…
Ladies and gentlemen, what you're witnessing…
正是一场痛快的复仇赛
is sweet dick-kicking revenge.
狠狠来一下
Oh! Giving him the business.
来了
Incoming!
这种行为太缺乏运动员精神了
This is taking unsportsmanlike conduct to a whole new level!
看上去不错啊 弗朗西斯 休息得挺好哈
Looking good, Francis. Well rested.
看着你被爆菊爆得挺多的呀
Like you've been pitching, not catching.
记得我不？不记得啦？
Ringing any bells? No?
那这样呢？
How about now?
韦德他妈的威尔逊
Wade fucking Wilson.
你好啊 帅哥
Well, hello, gorgeous.
我也跟蜘蛛侠一样呢 不过我是被沙皮狗咬了一口
Yeah, like I got bit by a radioactive Shar-Pei.
该怪谁呢 弗朗西斯？
Yeah. And whose fault is that, huh, Francis?
是时候该跟你就我这张丑爆的脸 好好算算账了
Yeah, time to undo what you did to this butterface.
拜托 你该谢谢我吧
Please, you should thank me.
显然是我造就了你永生
Apparently, I made you immortal.
我其实还挺嫉妒呢
I'm actually quite jealous.
是哦 不过这种生活可不快活 知道吗？
Yeah, but this ain't a life worth living, is it?
我要像90年代末软饼干乐队
Now, I'm about to do to you
糟蹋音乐那么糟蹋你
what Limp Bizkit did to music in the late 90s.
老爸？
Dad?
大家都同意很多事情
I think we can all agree that shit just went sideways
都不受控制
in the most colossal way.
好吧 或许还不是最糟的
Well, maybe not the most.
这是我最宝贝的东西
Uh… This is my most prized possession.
威猛乐队？
Wham?
不不不 是威猛乐队
No, no, no. Wham!
《飞黄腾达》这张专辑 是乔治和安迪的巅峰之作
Make It Big is the album that George and Andy earned the exclamation point.
那我是不是应该
So, am I supposed to just smile
笑着请你出去？
and wave you out the door?
就当做是春季大扫除嘛
Think of it like spring cleaning.
不过春天可能就等于死
Only if spring was death.
天呐 我这五分硬币的数量
God, if I had a nickel for every time
和对着伯娜黛特皮特丝撸的次数差不多啊
I spanked it to Bernadette Peters.
好像是这么回事呢
Sounds like you do.
伯娜黛特哪也不去
Bernadette is not going anywhere,
因为你哪也不去
because you're not going anywhere.
喝了
Drink.
没错 癌症也只在我的肝里
You're right. Cancer is only in my liver,
肺里 前列腺里 脑子里嘛
lungs, prostate, and brain.
没了这些我肯定还能活
All things I can live without.
你要呆在家
You belong here at home.
呆在你的战神金刚
Surrounded by your Voltron
你的伯娜黛特和你的我这里
and your Bernadette, and your me.
听着 你我都知道癌症就相当于完蛋
Listen, we both know that cancer is a shit-show.
完蛋到极点
Like, a Yakov-Smirnoff-opening-for-the
完蛋到不能更完蛋
Spin-Doctors-at-the-lowa-State-Fair shit-show.
我不可能让你卷进来
And under no circumstances will I take you to that show.
我希望你能记得我
I want you to remember me.
不是一个憔悴不堪的我
Not the ghost of Christmas me.
我想记住我们
Well, I wanna remember us.
我发誓 下辈子我还会找到你
I swear to God, I will find you in the next life…
我要在你的窗外 用手提音响放《无心快语》
and I'm gonna boom-box Careless Whisper outside your window.
威猛乐队
Wham!
别扯什么放歌行吗？
No one is boom-boxing shit. Okay?
我们会战胜癌症的
We can fight this.
而且 我刚刚意识到
Besides, I just realized something.
你赢了 你的生命比我的要糟糕多了
You win. Your life is officially way more fucked up than mine.
我爱你
I love you.
韦德
Wade.
鼹鼠
Weas.
你好像需要来杯「吹箫」 再去洗个澡啊
You look like you need a Blow Job and a shower.
礼貌起见 还是应该先洗澡
Though courtesy calls for the latter first.
来三杯帕特龙龙舌兰吧？
How about three shots of Patron?
不然来一把小麦草？
Or how about Triticum aestivum, wheatgrass.
对免疫系统好
Excellent for the immune system.
天呐 你这话听着就像瓦妮莎说的
Jesus Christ. You sound like Vanessa.
喏 看看这个
Here, check it out.
她预约了这么多 花花绿绿的医疗小册子上的诊所
She's sending away for all these colorful clinic brochures.
肯定全是通过食品和药物管理局审核的
I'm sure they're all FDA approved.
车臣 去那难道不是更容易得癌症吗？
Chechnya. Isn't that where you go to get cancer?
还有中国 墨西哥中部
You got China and Central Mexico.
知道他们怎么用西班牙语说「癌症」吗？
You know how they say "cancer" in Spanish?
不知道
No.
癌症
El Cancer.
我本来能猜出来的
I could have guessed that.
看看这张照片上你多开心
Look how happy you look here.
介意给我留着吗？把它挂起来
Mind if I keep this? Put it up,
这样我就能记得你生龙活虎时的样子了
so I can remember when you looked alive.
起码死亡赌局我要赢啦
At least now I'm gonna win the dead pool.
毕竟你要悲惨地死于癌症
Now that you're gonna die tragically of cancer.
我知道了 鼹鼠 谢谢
I got it, Weas. Thanks.
那边的那人是来找你的
And, uh, that guy over there came in looking for you.
这名片还真有死神的感觉
Real Grim Reaper type.
我也不知道 兴许能帮你活着演完呢
I don't know. Might further the plot.
布斯
Boothe.
韦德
Wade.
威尔逊先生
Mr. Wilson.
找我有什么事？
How can I help you?
除了帮你诱拐儿童到货车里
Besides luring children into a panel van.
我知道你最近被诊断出癌症晚期
I understand you've recently been diagnosed with terminal cancer.
你调查我？
Stalker alert.
这是我的职责 负责招人
It's my job. Recruitment.
很遗憾你现在过得很艰难
I'm sorry you've had such a tough go.
但你是名战士 属于特种部队
But you're a fighter. Special Forces.
服役期间杀死41人
41 confirmed kills.
每七周杀一个
One every seven weeks.
和人家理发的频率一样
Same rate most folks get a haircut.
为了能缓冲杀人的滋味
It's to wash the taste out.
要忘记杀人的滋味可不容易
It's tough to forget being so impressive.
如今你致力于
And now you spend your days
帮助那些可怜人…
sticking up for the little people…
人也会变 你想要什么？
People change. What do you want?
我代表一个组织而来 我们或许能帮到你
I represent an organization that may be able to help.
我要是告诉你我们可以治愈你的癌症呢？
What if I told you we can cure your cancer?
而且还能赋予你 大多数人都梦寐以求的能力？
And what's more, give you abilities most men only dream of?
我觉得你有点像电视上卖广告的
I'd say that you sound like an infomercial,
但卖的不是什么好东西
but not a good one, like Slap Chop.
像震动摇摆哑铃那种
More Shake Weight-y.
这世界需要非凡的战士
The world needs extraordinary soldiers.
我们不但能让你变得更好
We won't just make you better.
而且能让你比更好还好
We will make you better than better.
成为一个超级英雄
A superhero.
听着 史密斯特工
Look, Agent Smith,
英雄这档子事我做过 可没留下什么好底
I tried the hero business and it left a mark.
不过我要是最后改主意了 我会联系你的
But if I ever hit "fuck it", I'll look you up.
糟了 这附近就有一所学校
Shit. We're within 500 yards of a school,
所以你走的时候得…
so you may wanna…
他喝的自己付钱
His drink's on him.
他说了什么？
What did he say?
嘿 你怎么了？
Hey, what's going on?
嘿 抱歉
Hey. Sorry.
我做噩梦梦到连姆尼森了
I had a Liam Neeson nightmare.
我梦到自己绑架了他女儿
I dreamt I kidnapped his daughter
他老生气了
and he just wasn't having it.
嘿 《飓风营救》拍了三部
Hey, uh, they've made three of those movies.
看电影时 会让人不得不想 他到底是不是个好父亲
At some point you have to wonder if he's just a bad parent.
癌症最可怕的 不是它对你的影响
The worst part about cancer isn't what it does to you…
而是它对你爱的人造成的影响
but what it does to the people you love.
谁知道那人能不能救我的命…
Who knew if this guy could save my life…
而我却清楚 要救她 只有这一种办法
but I knew there was only one way that I could save hers.
超级英雄不就是这样吗？
Isn't that what superheroes do?
好嘞 我们来列一个 当超级英雄好处和坏处的单子
Okay. Let's pro-con this superhero thing.
好处 一大帮辣妹恨不得让你扑倒
Pro: They pull down a gaggle of ass.
能享受当地干洗折扣
Local dry cleaning discounts.
能拍电影赚大钱 不管是原创个人故事
Lucrative film deals, both origin stories
还是组队打怪电影
and larger ensemble team movies.
坏处 他们都是可怜的听话乖宝宝
Con: They're all lame-ass teacher's pets.
你知道 我能听到你说话
You know, I can hear you.
我又不是在跟你说 我在跟观众说
I wasn't talking to you. I was talking to them.
呆在这别动
Stay right here.
你收到过警告 死侍
You've been warned before, Deadpool.
你这么用你的能力 显得十分鲁莽 可耻
This is a shameful and reckless use of your powers.
你俩我们都要押回去
You will both be coming with us.
听着 钢巨人 我现在没时间
Look, Colossus, I don't have time for
跟你扯什么正义不正义 该不该做
the goody two-shoes bullshit right now!
你是？
And you are?
黑后少年弹头
Negasonic Teenage Warhead.
黑后少年… 什么鬼？
Negasonic Teenage… What the shit?
简直是我听过最炫酷的名字
That's the coolest name ever!
所以你是他的副手？
So, what, you're like, uh, his sidekick?
不 是受训人
No. Trainee.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
X战警把你留下来干嘛？做这种烦心事？
X-Men left you behind on what? Shit detail?
那你要干什么？
What does that make you?
假装你不在这啊 黑后少年弹头
Pretending you're not here, Negasonic Teenage Warhead.
我们能换个名字吗？
Can we trade names?
我们可以走吗？
Can we go?
看呀 我还是个少女呢
Look! I'm a teenage girl.
我去哪也不来这
I'd rather be anywhere than here.
我不开心啦 不说话啦
I'm all about long sullen silences…
我要发脾气骂人啦 然后又要不作声啦
followed by mean comments, followed by more silences.
所以你到底会怎么做呢？是生闷气不作声呢
So what's it gonna be, huh? Long sullen silence…
还是发脾气骂人？说吧
or mean comment? Go on.
我说不过你
You got me in a box here.
我们不允许这种行为 死侍
We can't allow this, Deadpool.
拜托 安安静静地跟我们走吧
Please, come quietly.
你个大蠢驴铁块
You big chrome cock-gobbler!
这么说可不够友好
That's not nice.
你真要坏我的事？
You're really gonna fuck this up for me?
相信我 那个傻逼他活该
Trust me, that wheezing bag of dick-tips has it coming.
他就是个十足的混蛋
He's pure evil.
而且… 也没人受伤啊
Besides… Nobody's getting hurt.
我到这的时候他就已经在那了
That guy was already up there when I got here.
韦德 你不至于这样
Wade, you are better than this.
- 加入我们吧 用你的能力去做好事 - 抬头
- Join us. Use your powers for good. - Heads up.
做一个超级英雄
Be a superhero.
听好了
Listen!
在我决定要成为打击犯罪的恶棍的那天
The day I decide to become a crime-fighting shit-swizzler…
决定和另一帮怨声载道的人 在梦幻庄园做室友时
who rooms with a bunch of other little whiners at the Neverland mansion…
庄园的主人还是个又老又丑的秃头
of some creepy, old, bald,
长得就像信了邪教似的一个混蛋
Heaven's Gate-looking motherfucker…
就在那天
on that day…
我会发送给你一个 闪闪发光 快乐的好友请求
I'll send your shiny, happy ass a friend request.
但在那之前 我要把我来这的目的完成
But until then, I'mma do what I came here to do.
不让我做 我就一巴掌呼死你
Either that or slap the bitch outta you!
- 韦德 - 嘿
- Wade… - Hey.
闭嘴 小平头
Zip it, Sinéad!
嘿 死傻
Hey, douche-pool!
我希望你在看…
And I hope you're watching…
真可惜
Quite unfortunate.
去他的
That does it!
加拿大
Canada!
这可不好
That's not good.
韦德 拜托
Wade, please.
击裆
Cock shot!
你老婆真可怜
Oh, your poor wife.
你真该住手了
You really should stop.
恐龙都怕霸王龙吧
All the dinosaurs feared the T. rex.
我保证有你好看的 大块头
I promise this gets worse for you, big boy!
真是尴尬
This is embarrassing.
拜托 别起来
Please, stay down.
听说过一条腿也能打架的人吗？
You ever hear of the one-legged man in the ass-kicking contest?
你身上有开关能关上吗？
Do you have off switch?
有啊 就在前列腺旁边
Yeah, it's right next to the prostate.
可能是打开的开关哦？
Or is that the on switch?
够了
Enough!
我们去和X教授谈一谈
Let us go talk to the Professor.
麦卡沃伊演的还是斯图尔特演的？
McAvoy or Stewart?
时间线真是混乱啊
These timelines are so confusing.
「不管是生是死 你都要跟我走」
"Dead or alive, you're coming with me!"
你会恢复的 韦德
You will recover, Wade.
你一向都能自我恢复
You always do.
看过《127小时》吗？剧透提示
You ever see 127 Hours? Spoiler alert.
噢 天呐
Oh, my God.
真恶心
Nasty.
这里可是卖点啊 宝贝
Oh, there's the money shot, baby.
天啊 我来啦
Are You There God? It's Me, Margaret.
不能更倒霉了
Rock, meet bottom.
当生活极其不如意时
And when life ends up breathtakingly fucked…
你可以回想下某个重大的 糟糕的决定
you can generally trace it back to one big, bad decision.
那个一路把你带到谷底的决定
The one that sent you down the road to Shitsburgh.
这个？这就是我的那个决定
This? Well, this was mine.
威尔逊先生
Mr. Wilson.
最让我暖心的事 就是别人改变心意了
Nothing warms my heart more than a change of someone else's.
你终于决定了
You finally hit "fuck it."
答应我你要对得起我
Just promise you'll do right by me.
这样我才对得起另一个人
So I can do right by someone else.
这是当然
Of course.
别把战服做成绿色的啊
And please don't make the super-suit green.
上面也不要有动画啊
Or animated.
移过去 继续
Move it! Keep moving.
这地儿还真是卫生呢
This place seems sanitary.
我的第一个要求就是抬我的人手要暖点
My first request is warmer hands.
还有 我的天 手术台也要暖点
Oh! And, Jesus, a warmer table.
我们真该想个安全暗号 伙计们
We should really come up with a safe word, fellas.
我在想「猪肉和豆子」怎么样
I'm thinking "pork and beans."
轻点
Easy.
你身为一个女的 劲儿也太大了吧
Aren't you a little strong for a lady?
你肯定长了小弟弟吧
I'm calling wang.
叼根火柴干嘛？
What's up with the matches?
修整牙齿的？还是模仿史泰龙？
Oral fixation or just a big Stallone fan?
耐心点 安琪尔
Patience, Angel.
以后有的是时间
All in good time.
你是来铺床的还是干嘛的？
Are you here for the turndown service, or what?
又来一个话多的
We have another talker.
我第一天加入超级英雄阵营太激动了
I'm just excited about my first day at superhero camp.
你他妈闭嘴
Shut the fuck up.
威尔逊先生 我叫阿贾克斯
Mr. Wilson, my name's Ajax.
这个工作坊是我开的
I manage this workshop.
我们过去的欢迎词中全是婉言 比如说
Ah, my welcome speech used to be full of euphemisms like…
「可能会有一点点痛」
"This may hurt a little."
「你可能会感到一点点不适」
"This may cause you some discomfort."
不过我现在诚实多了
But I've grown blunt.
这个工作坊的项目不是由政府牵头的
This workshop is not a government-led program.
是个私人机构 专门把你这样的回收物
It's a private institution that turns reclamation projects like yourself…
变成具有超能力的人
into men of extraordinary abilities.
不过你要是以为超能力 可以不付代价就获得…
But if you think super-human powers are acquired painlessly…
那就错了
Wrong.
我现在给你注射一种血清
I'm injecting you with a serum…
可以激活你的DNA中潜在的突变基因
that activates any mutant genes lurking in your DNA.
为了让其有效 我们需要让你承受极端的压力
For it to work we need to subject you to extreme stress.
你也听说过「要做蛋卷 先打碎蛋」吧？
You've heard that whole "make an omelet, break some eggs" bit, right?
我会让你很痛的 韦德
I'm about to hurt you, Wade.
我曾经也是这里的一名病人
I was a patient here once myself, you know.
治疗对于每个人的效果都不同
The treatment affects everyone differently.
安琪尔因此变得超乎常人得强壮
It made Angel inhumanly strong.
至于我 我的反射能力得以提升
In my case, it enhanced my reflexes.
也烧焦了我的神经末梢 让我感觉不到疼痛
Also scorched my nerve endings, so I no longer feel pain.
其实 我什么也感觉不到了
And, in fact, I no longer feel anything.
谢谢 多谢 多谢
Thanks! Thank you. Thank you.
你牙齿里有东西
You have something in your teeth.
就在正中间 我没…
Right in the middle there. Just, I don't…
应该是片生菜还是什么的
A little nugget of romaine lettuce or something.
我看着闹心了好一会儿呢
It's been bothering me for a long time.
骗到你啦
Ah, made you look.
嘿 阿贾克斯是你的真名吗？
Hey, is Ajax your actual name?
听上去像是你编出来的一样
Because it sounds suspiciously made up.
你真名叫什么？
What is it, really?
凯文？布鲁斯？斯科特？
Kevin? Bruce? Scott?
米奇？里克斯特？
Mitch? The Rickster?
还是巴西弗尔蒂？
Is it Basil Fawlty?
笑话真够多的
Oh, joke away.
幽默感在这里
One thing that never survives this place
从来就留不长久
is a sense of humor.
我们等着瞧
We'll see about that.
我也这么想
I suppose we will.
他交给你了
He's all yours.
不是吧
Oh, come on.
你要把我留在这
You're gonna leave me all alone here
和火气没那么大的罗茜欧唐内单独共处？
with less-angry Rosie O'Donnell?
就是这样
This is how it's going to work.
肾上腺素是这种血清的催化剂
Adrenaline acts as a catalyst for the serum…
所以我们要你不好受
so we're going to have to make you suffer.
你走运的话 突变基因会被激活
If you're lucky, the mutant genes will activate
并以非常壮观的方式表达出来
and manifest in a spectacular fashion.
要是不幸 我们就得继续折磨你…
If not, well, we'll have to keep on hurting you…
用新的 不同的方法折磨
in new and different ways,
每一个都更令人痛苦
each more painful than the last…
直到最后你发生突变
until you finally mutate.
或者死掉
Or die.
你是说人生清单？
You mean a bucket list?
还狗生清单呢
Like a fuck-it list.
我想用奥运火炬点根烟
I'd really like to light a spliff off the Olympic torch.
然后给我来一口
Pass it to me right after.
别忘了和WNBA萨克拉门托君主队队员
Let's not forget naked tandem base-jumping
双人裸体定点跳伞
with the WNBA's Sacramento Monarchs.
我的清单里肯定有在公共场合裸露
Anything on my bucket list would involve public nudity.
最后把梅雷迪斯巴克斯特闷在被子里 闻一闻我在里面放的屁
Finally, giving Meredith Baxter-Birney a Dutch oven.
不 闻梅雷迪斯巴克斯特的屁
No. Receiving a Dutch oven from Meredith Baxter-Birney.
给我的孩子们做香蕉烙饼
Making banana pancakes for my kids.
瓦妮莎
Vanessa.
我想见瓦妮莎
I wanna see Vanessa.
你真可爱呢
You're lovely.
我虽然不知道你说的是谁 但我很感动
I don't know about anyone else, but I'm touched.
我们只是在开玩笑
We were just joking.
不 没关系
No, no. It's okay.
我鼓励你们分散注意力
I encourage distractions.
我不希望你们就这么放弃 好吗？
Wouldn't want you giving up on us, now would we?
嘿 别他妈任他摆弄 坎宁安
Hey, don't take any shit from him, Cunningham.
他能有多厉害
How tough can he be…
就凭他叫弗朗西斯这种名字？
with a name like Francis?
弗朗西斯？
Francis?
那是他合法登记的名字
That's his legal name.
「阿贾克斯」 这名字是他借鉴洗洁精来的
He got "Ajax" from the dish soap.
F-R-A-N-C-I…
哎哟
Oops!
我从你的白大褂上 顺下来这个干洗的名字牌
Snagged the dry cleaning tag off your lab coat.
（弗里曼 弗朗西斯）
顺便一说 说不定 我能给你个超级英雄的折扣
FYI, I could probably get you the superhero discount.
你真是无休止地讨人嫌
You are so relentlessly annoying.
谢谢
Thanks.
这话我还没听过呢
Never heard that before.
你行行好闭上你那张臭嘴行吗？
Why don't you do us all a favor and shut the fuck up?
不然我就把你的嘴封上
Or I'll sew your pretty mouth shut.
我要是你就不会这么做
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
这种没个头的折磨有个问题…
See, here's the problem with round-the-clock torture…
你没法真正地加强程度或提高频率
is that you can't really step it up from there.
你是这么认为的？
Is that what you think?
如果这还不能激活你突变 那…
If this doesn't unlock your mutation, then, well…
就没什么能激活了
nothing will.
现在我们要
Now, what we're going to do is
降低空气中的氧气浓度
lower the oxygen concentration in the air…
直到你感觉将要窒息
to the exact point you feel like you're suffocating.
如果你的脑电波慢下来
If your brainwaves slow,
也就是意味着你即将失去知觉
meaning you're about to pass out…
我们就会补充氧气
then we'll turn up the O2.
如果你心率降低
If your heart rate slows…
也就是说你喘得过来气
meaning you're able to catch your breath…
我们就会停止氧气供给
we'll turn it back down.
你就在那经受这些吧
And that's where we'll leave you. Right there.
你们以前一定是大混蛋
Oh, and I thought you guys were dicks before.
知道最有意思的是什么吗？
You know the funniest part of this?
你还以为我们在把你变成超级英雄呢
You still think we're making you a superhero.
你 一个可耻的退伍兵
You. A dishonorable discharge.
只知道和妓女鬼混
Hip-deep in hookers.
你什么也不是
You're nothing.
告诉你个小秘密吧 韦德
Little secret, Wade.
这个工作坊不制造超级英雄
This workshop doesn't make superheroes,
我们制造的是超级奴隶
we make super-slaves.
我们会给你定制一个控制颈圈
We're gonna fit you with a control collar
然后把你卖给出价最高的客户
and auction you off to the highest bidder.
谁知道他们会让你做什么呢？
Who knows what they'll have you doing?
恐吓平民 虐杀为自由而战的人
Terrorizing citizens, putting down freedom fighters.
说不定只是偶尔让你割割草
Maybe just mow the occasional lawn.
你他妈有什么毛病？
What the fuck is wrong with you?
经历过这些 你不可能回家了
You're never going home after this.
看看你这张英勇的面庞
Now there's a brave face.
等等 等等
Wait, wait! Wait. Wait.
说真的 你的牙齿上真的有东西
Seriously, you actually have something in your teeth now.
周末快乐
Enjoy your weekend.
「周末」 ？说什么？
"Weekend"? Back up.
周末？
Weekend?
我说过这是个爱情故事吗？
Did I say this was a love story?
不 其实是部惊悚片
No, it's a horror movie.
真恶心
Fucking hell.
看来有人当不上返校舞会的国王了
Looks like someone lost his shot at Homecoming King.
你对我做了什么？
What have you done to me?
我只是增加了你的压力值
I've merely raised your stress levels
好触发你发生突变啊
high enough to trigger a mutation.
你个混蛋虐待狂
You sadistic fuck!
我治好了你的癌症 韦德
I've cured you, Wade.
如今你的变异细胞什么都能治愈
Now your mutated cells can heal anything.
它们正在攻击你的癌细胞 和形成的速度一样快
It's attacking your cancer as fast as it can form.
我之前也见过类似的副作用
Yeah, I've seen similar side-effects before.
我能治好
I could cure them…
但这不就没意思了吗？
but where's the fun in that?
我要再次把你关起来 韦德
Now, I'm gonna shut you in again, Wade.
不是出于需要
Not because I need to.
而是因为我想这么玩
Because I want to.
好吧
Oh, well.
继续
Go ahead.
你闻着就像便便一样
Oh, you smell like shit.
妈的
Motherfucker.
嘿 嘿 淡定 没关系
Hey, hey, hey. It's all right, it's all right.
就算我们欠他的 好吗？
I think we owe him that one, yeah?
你先走吧 走吧
You take off. Go on.
走吧
Off you go.
一个小问题
Quick question.
我叫什么？
What's my name?
看来你不会回答了
Didn't think so.
抱歉 弗朗西斯 我的嘴唇被封起来了
Sorry, Francis. My lips are sealed.
（氧气）
（氧气 冷冻 液体）
你不会杀我的
You don't want to kill me.
只有我能治好你这张丑脸
I'm the only one who can fix your ugly mug.
我叫什么？
What's my name?
韦德
Wade.
我不仅被治好了癌症…
I didn't just get the cure to el cancer…
而且什么都能被治好
I got the cure to el everything.
但只有一件事…
But there was only one thing…
很麻烦
that really mattered.
来吧 我们走
Come on, let's go.
噢 一定很疼
Oh, that must hurt.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
我去 一脸瘤啊
God, he's so fucking gnarly.
快看他脸
Look at his face.
噢 天呐 他好可怜
Oh, my God. Poor guy.
宝贝 别盯着人家看
Honey, don't stare.
怪人
Freak.
不行 我不能让她的生活和我的一样丑陋
No way. I'm not making her life as ugly as mine.
别啊 韦德 不会那么糟的
Come on, Wade, it can't be that bad.
狗屁
Ah, bullshit!
我从内到外都是个怪物 我就该去个该死的马戏团
I'm a monster inside and out. I belong in a fucking circus.
韦德 瓦妮莎爱你 她不会在乎你…
Wade, Vanessa loves you. She doesn't care what you…
你喜欢你眼前的这副样子吗？
Do you like what you see?
不
No.
你就像一只鳄梨
You look like an avocado
和另一只更老更丑的鳄梨生下来的
had sex with an older, more disgusting avocado.
是啊
Yeah.
而且还没好好传宗接代 像是被强暴后生下来的
Not gently. Like it was hate-fucking.
那两只鳄梨关系出了问题
There was something wrong with the relationship…
你的脸是他们唯一不用暴力解决
and that was the only catharsis
而排出来的东西
that they could find without violence.
唯一能治好这张丑脸的人
And the only guy who can fix this fugly mug…
就是那个突变工厂的英国恶搞老板
is the British shitstick who ran the mutant factory.
他跑了 嘭
And he's gone. Poof!
你得做些什么来补救
Yeah, well you gotta do something to remedy this…
因为照现在来看
because as of now,
你这张脸只有一种办法可以挽救
you only have one course of action.
真对
Damn straight.
- 找到弗朗西斯 - 演惊悚片
- Find Francis. - Star in horror films.
什么？
What?
拍你自己的惊悚片
Star in your own horror films.
你看上去就像《猛鬼街》里弗莱迪克鲁格
Because you look like Freddy Krueger
上了一张犹他州的地形图
face-fucked a topographical map of Utah.
我打算这么做
Here's what I'm actually gonna do.
我要把他手下的人 从下弄到上
I'm gonna work through his crew
直到掏出弗朗西斯的消息
until somebody gives up Francis…
逼他修好我的脸 然后一枪毙了他
force him to fix this, then put a bullet in his skull…
然后冲着他脑袋上的洞来一炮
and fuck the brain hole.
这画面真让我不敢想更不敢看
I don't wanna see that or think of it again.
不过那个混蛋是以为你死了吧？
But the douchebag does thinks you're dead, right?
对
Yeah.
很好 你就一直让他以为你死了
That's good. You should keep it that way.
怎么 戴副面具什么的？
What, like, wear a mask?
对 一副非常厚的面具 一直戴着
Yes. A very thick mask. All the time.
不好意思
I am sorry…
你这张脸太难忘了
you are haunting.
简直就是噩梦
Your face is the stuff of nightmares.
像是长了牙齿的蛋蛋是吧
Like a testicle with teeth.
你到死都娶不到妹子的
You will die alone.
前提是你能死
I mean, if you could die.
希望如此 这是为大家好
Ideally, for others' sake.
够了
That'll do.
你现在需要一身战服和一个外号
All you need now is a suit and a nickname…
比如韦德「逗你玩」
like Wade the Wisecracker…
或者恐怖恶魔 不死先生
or Scaredevil, Mr. Neverdie.
该死
Oh, shit.
怎么了？
What?
我把钱都押在你身上了 现在
I put all my money on you and now…
我刚刚才想到 我是不可能赢
I just realized I'm never gonna win the, uh…
死侍
Dead pool.
（玛格丽特酒吧死亡赌局）
死侍队长
Captain Deadpool…
不 就叫…
No, just…
- 就叫死侍 对 - 就叫死侍
- Just Deadpool, yeah. - Just Deadpool.
敬你 死侍先生
To you, Mr. Pool.
死侍
Deadpool.
听上去好卖座的名字
That sounds like a fucking franchise.
我要去好好折磨折磨人了
This shit's gonna have nuts in it.
弗朗西斯去哪了？
Where's Francis?
弗朗西斯在哪？
苏打水加柠檬 去血渍
Seltzer water and lemon for blood.
直接穿红的不就行了 蠢货
Or wear red. Dumbass.
别让我再问一遍
Don't make me ask twice.
在哪？
Where…
弗朗西斯在哪？
is Francis?
他让我问了两遍
He made me ask twice.
这面具是不是隔音？
Is the mask muffling my voice?
弗朗西斯在哪？
Where's Francis?
弗朗西斯他妈的在哪？
Where the fuck is Francis?
你会被磨冰机给碾死的
You're about to be killed by a Zamboni.
弗朗西斯在哪？
Where's Francis?
不要 求求你
No! Please!
哦 天呐 我好抱歉哟
Oh, God! I'm so sorry!
你个小蜘蛛猴
Oh! You little spider monkey!
弗朗西斯… 在… 哪里？
Where… is… Francis?
好纠结啊
This is confusing.
打你是不是性别歧视啊？
Is it sexist to hit you?
不打你会不会是更严重的性别歧视？
Is it more sexist to not hit you?
这其中的界限真是… 模糊呢
I mean, the line gets real… blurry.
弗朗西斯在哪？
WHERE IS FRANCIS?
告诉我你那个该死的老板在哪
Tell me where your fucking boss is
不说你就去死
or you're gonna die!
倒数五分钟
In five minutes!
（磨冰机小子）
（史密斯特工）
打给我别犹豫
Don't hesitate to call me.
你好啊 杰拉德
Nice to see you, Jared.
我要个12寸的三明治…
I'll take the footlong…
要加满料
Fully loaded.
服役期间杀死41人
41 confirmed kills.
现在是89条人命了 马上就到90了
Now it's 89. About to be 90.
威尔逊先生？
Mr. Wilson?
叮… 叮
Ding-ding.
你看上去真是生龙活虎
You're looking very alive.
只有外在活着
Ha! Only on the outside!
- 我不会有善终的 是吗？- 你不会有善终 是的
- This is not going to end well for me, is it? - This is not gonna end well for you, no.
你老板在哪？
Where's your boss?
我能确切地告诉你…
I can tell you exactly…
你要告诉我 不过首先…
Oh, you'll tell me. But first…
你们不会想看这个画面的
You might wanna look away for this.
现在这几只小猪仔要…
Now this little piggy went to…
多谢了 史密斯特工
Thank you, Agent Smith.
出租车
Taxi!
上车吧 今天是个坐车的好日子
Hop in! Great day for a ride.
之后是怎么回事我们都清楚了
And we all know how this turned out.
呀 不该给你们看到这个
Whoops! You weren't meant to see that.
到这 都接上了
There. All caught up.
到了
We're here.
抱歉把血都流到你的垃圾里了
Sorry about bleeding in all your garbage.
可以用苏打水和柠檬去血渍
Seltzer water and lemon for blood.
有些怒火是控制不了的
Some kinds of anger can't be managed…
比如说 你花了那么久找一个人
like the kind where your year-long plan
结果自己的手却被割断了
ends with the wrong guy getting dismembered!
不过 要疗伤的话
That said, when it comes time to licking wounds,
家里才是不二之选
there's no place like home.
我的室友你们也见过
Ah, and I share that home with someone you've met,
就是干洗店那位看不见的老太太 阿尔
the old blind lady from the laundromat, Al.
老天呐 我真想抽可卡因
God, I miss cocaine.
就是她
Her.
角色表演里跳出角色表演
Fourth-wall break inside a fourth-wall break.
那可是天下无敌啊
That's like 16 walls.
我是蝙蝠侠的话 她就是罗宾
She's like Robin to my Batman,
除了她又老又黑又瞎
except she's old, and black, and blind.
我觉得她爱上我了
And I think she's in love with me.
等等 罗宾肯定也爱蝙蝠侠
Wait, pretty sure Robin loves Batman, too.
阿尔？
Al?
早上好 老懒虫
Morning, sleepyhead.
这里闻着就像是老太太的裤子
It smells like old lady pants in here.
是啊 我是老了 我也穿着裤子
Yes, I'm old. I wear pants.
但你不是淑女
But you're no lady.
真舒服
Oh! So comfy.
瞎了眼的一个好处 我从没见过你穿洞洞鞋的样子
Upside of being blind: I've never seen you in Crocs.
你指的是我那双 撸的时候专门穿的大橡胶鞋？
You mean my big, rubber masturbating shoes?
是 我知道
Yes, I know.
瞎了的坏处
Downside of being blind…
在这间小破屋里我什么都能听清
I hear everything in this duplex.
行了闭嘴吧
Sit on a stick.
抗生软膏？
Bactin?
行 抗生软膏就可以
Yeah. Bactin should do it.
那个库伦柜是怎么来的？
How's that Kullen coming along?
宜家可不会自己组装好送来
IKEA doesn't assemble itself, you know.
可不是嘛 我倒是不讨厌库伦柜
You're telling me. I don't mind the Kullen.
那是对赫达尔柜的改进
It's an improvement on the Hurdal.
得了吧 什么都是对赫达尔柜的改进
Please. Anything's an improvement over the Hurdal.
我还说汉尼斯和特利希尔 都是对赫达尔的改进呢
I'd have taken an Hemnes or a Trysil over the Hurdal.
不 我看到库伦柜时才兴奋起来
Oh, no, I didn't get excited till I saw the Kullen.
把螺丝钉递给我 谢谢
Screw, please.
在这？现在？开玩笑吧
Here? Now? Just kidding.
我知道你这几十年都没有过性生活
I know it's been decades.
可不是你以为的那样
You'd be surprised.
真恶心呢
Pretty grossed out.
当… 当
Ta… Da.
真希望我从没听说过克雷格分类广告网
I wish I never heard of Craigslist.
我在上面的介绍是这样的“找室友
And I quote, "Looking for roommate,
盲人最好 免得受惊
"blind to life's imperfections.
手要灵巧”
"Must be good with hands."
不然你更愿意 我来组装宜家的家具 你来付房租？
Or would you rather I build the IKEA, and you pay rent?
你今天早上怎么这么贱？
Why such a douche this morning?
我来总结一下
Let's recap.
把我变成这幅摸样的那个龟儿子
The cock thistle that turned me into this freak…
今天从我的手中溜了
slipped through my arms today…
我的手
Arm.
只有抓到他 我才有希望
Catching him was my only chance
重新变帅 追回我超级性感的前女友
to be hot again, get my super sexy ex back…
避免其他人再遭遇同样的破事
and prevent this shit from happening to someone else.
对啊 今天就跟
So, yeah, today was about as much fun
用个砂纸做的自慰器自慰一样有趣
as a sandpaper dildo.
擦身而过放个屁
Driveby.
我知道穿红衣服的那位朋友是谁了
Found out who our friend in the red suit is.
该死的韦德威尔逊
Fucking Wade Wilson.
我要是脸变成那样 我也会戴面具
I suppose I'd wear a mask too if I had a face like that.
不过我只希望我有和他一样的愈合能力
I only wish I healed the same.
不过 我们还是得除了这个灾星
Still, we'll put him out of our misery.
用我们的方式
On our terms.
好啊 然后等他愈合？
Right. And when he heals?
他不行
He can't.
只要他没什么可愈合的
Not if there's nothing left of him to heal.
你知道吗 还真有意思 我差点想念这混蛋了
You know, it's funny. I almost miss the fucker.
我喜欢挑战
I like a challenge.
但他不利于我们的工作
But he's bad for business.
我们去找他吧
Now let's go find him.
扑热息痛？
Tylenol PM?
不要抗生软膏也不要这个
You can stick that where you stuck the Bactin.
我抓了智齿止痛药
I raided my stash of wisdom tooth Percocet…
吃了药现在又犯困
and I am orbiting fucking Saturn right now.
不过还是谢谢你给我药
But I appreciate the gesture.
我是疯了 还是你的手真的就这么小？
Am I crazy, or is your hand really small?
和肯德基的餐叉差不多大小
About the size of a KFC spork.
我知道你为什么这么暴躁了
I get why you're so pissy…
不过除非你找到这个女人
but your mood's never gonna brighten
并告诉她你的感受
till you find this woman…
你的心情才可能好起来
and tell her how you feel.
要我说多少次 脱线太太？
What do I keep telling you, Mrs. Magoo?
她不可能跟我复合的
She wouldn't have me.
你要是能看见我 你就明白了
If you could see me, you'd understand.
外表不是一切
Looks aren't everything.
外表就是一切
Looks are everything.
听过大卫贝克汉姆的声音吗？
You ever heard David Beckham speak?
就像他吞了一罐氮气似的
It's like he mouth-sexed a can of helium.
你以为瑞安雷诺兹
You think Ryan Reynolds got this far
是靠演技才走到今天的？
on his superior acting method?
爱情是盲目的 韦德
Love is blind, Wade.
不是
No.
你是盲人
You're blind.
那你就准备躺在这呜咽个不停？
So, you're just gonna lie there and whimper?
不 我要等这只手长过了青春期
No, I'm gonna wait till this arm plows through puberty…
然后就要想出个全新的圣诞节计划
and then I'm gonna come up with a whole new Christmas Day plan.
与此同时
In the meantime,
你可能想离开这间房
you might wanna leave the room.
我打赌用这只手打枪的话 肯定感觉我的老二特别大
I bet it feels huge in this hand.
快走快走
Go, go!
所以医生说：「坏消息是
So, the doctor says, "The bad news is
你活不了那么久了「
you don't have that long to live."
病人就问：「我还能活多久？」
So, the patient says, "How long do I have?"
医生说：「五」
The doctor says, "Five."
那人问：「五什么？」
The guy says, "Five what?"
医生说：「四 三 二… 」
And the doctor says, "Four, three, two…"
女士们 需要什么吗？
Can I help you ladies?
希望你能提供些什么
Oh, I do hope so.
我听说你或许能帮我指出
I heard you might be able to point me
我的一个朋友在哪个方向
in the direction of a, um, friend of mine.
他叫韦德威尔逊
Name of Wade Wilson.
不好意思
Sorry.
我没听说过这名字
I don't know the name.
嘿 你不能到吧台后面来
Hey, you're not supposed to be behind the bar.
我见过这女孩
I've seen this girl.
这一定就是瓦妮莎
Ah, this must be Vanessa.
我听说过你好多次呢
I've heard so much about you.
亲爱的 你或许想看看四周
Um, sweetheart, you might wanna look around.
这里真不是做这种事的地方
This isn't really the place to do something like that.
别冲动 安琪尔
Easy, Angel.
把这位小兄弟放下来
Put the little man down.
我们需要的已经拿到手了
We have everything we need now.
你确定？
You sure?
你难道不想要一件 颜色不那么单一的衣服吗？
You don't want any clothes that are not monochromatic?
祝你们在《刀锋战士2》午夜场玩得开心
Have fun at your midnight showing of Blade II.
谢谢你们帮我 兄弟们
Thanks for having my back, guys.
韦德 我们有大麻烦了
Wade, we have a fucking problem.
「我们」其实是指「你」
And by "we, " I mean "you."
我不相信我在这么做
Ah, I can't believe I'm doing this.
有没有一个词可以形容 一半害怕一半生气？
Is there a word for half afraid, half angry?
有「害生」 我猜的
Yeah, "afrangry", I guess.
你想好要怎么和她说了吗？
Have you decided what you're gonna say to her?
妈的
Fuck me!
最好不用一开始就说这个
Uh, maybe not start with that.
嘿 现在上台的是
Hey, coming onto our stage right now…
让我们欢迎「贞操小姐」
give it up for Chastity!
我比较喜欢喊她「讽刺小姐」
Or as I like to call her, Irony.
最好在那帮傻蛋之前赶紧找到她
Better find her fast before numbnuts does.
你怎么知道她在这里？
How do you know she's in here?
因为我经常跟踪那位辣妹
Because I'm constantly stalking that fox.
我每次见到她 感觉都像是第一次见她
Every time I see her, it's like the first time…
尤其是从这个角度
Especially from this angle.
爱情是买不来的
You can't buy love,
但可以租个三分钟
but you can rent it for three minutes.
你个懦夫
Ah, you weak motherfucker!
加油
Come on!
加油 振作起来
Come on, get it together.
不是为了我自己 是为了瓦妮莎
This isn't about me, this is about Vanessa.
上吧
Here we go.
全力前进
Maximum effort.
瓦妮莎
Vanessa.
后面有人找你
Someone out back asking for you.
说跟你前男友有关
Something about, uh, an old boyfriend.
我知道是你
I knew it was you.
这个特别的线条
The weird, curvy edges.
像块拼图
Like a jigsaw puzzle.
这还真得谢谢韦德威尔逊
You have Wade Wilson to thank for this.
嘿 嘿 她去哪了？
Hey. Hey! Where'd she go?
我看到她去后面了
Uh, I saw her head to the back.
去找她吧 勇士
Go get her, tiger.
他妈的
Fuck. Fuck!
去他妈的
Motherfucker!
- 等等 等等 我们先… - 去你…
- Wait, wait. Let's… Just… - Cock juggling…
- 我们可以先讨论一下… - 我去 你个球
- We can talk about what we're gonna… - Jiminy! Fuck face!
好嘞 你也可以打那个
Okay, or you can hit that.
- 对 对 对 - 妈的 妈的
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. - Fuck! Fuck!
- 行了 行了 嘿 - 妈的 妈的
- No, no. All right. Hey! - Fuck! Fuck!
- 妈的 - 嘿…
- Fuck! - Hey, um…
淡定 淡定 好了
Whoa! Whoa! Relax. Relax. Okay.
好了 我想这是个好的开始
Okay. I think that's a good start.
我要把那个混蛋撕碎…
Oh, I'm gonna rip his motherfucking…
等等
Wait.
- 找到它 找到它 - 什么？
- Find it! Find it. - What?
- 我要发脾气了 - 好 好的
- I'm gonna get angry. - Okay. All right.
好的 行 好的
All right. Okay. All right.
在这 是瓦妮莎
Here. This is Vanessa.
- 什么？- 不 等下 是弗朗西斯
- What? - No, wait. It's Francis.
他要你去找他
He wants you to come to him.
（想要她吗？来找她 废品场 中午12点 爱你）
- 那是什么？- 是个屎的表情
- What is that? - That's the shit emoji.
就是带着笑脸和眼睛的一坨屎
You know, it's the turd with the smiling face and the eyes?
我有好长时间都以为这是巧克力酸奶
I thought it was chocolate yogurt for so long.
我要枪
I need guns.
好的 哪一只枪？
Okay, which ones?
我要所有枪
I need all the guns!
好的 好
All right. Okay.
（世界上最性感的男人 休杰克曼）
大概有3000颗子弹
That's about 3, 000 rounds.
我们都知道12颗就能解决问题
We all know what I can do with 12.
嘿 嘿 当心点那个 罗尼米尔萨普
Hey, hey, careful with that, Ronnie Milsap!
对着我们呢
We're downrange.
我今晚本来在
I was gonna spend the night
组装博尔基椅子 不过这个倒是引起了我的兴趣
assembling the Borje, but this is holding my interest.
我跟你说过 我们要尤瓦吉椅 不是博尔基椅
I told you, we're going with the Urvaj, not the Borje.
你给我记住了 不然就滚
Get it through your head or get out of fuck town.
该死 房子里所有的枪都在这了
Shit. That's all the pieces in the house.
不 来 过来 拿出来
Nah, nah… Come on. Let's go. Cough it up.
拉起来 拉起来
Up, up, up.
放下去 放下去
Oh. Down, down, down.
去你的
Fuck you.
0.45的口径 我喜欢
.45 cal. I like it.
韦德…
Wade…
我应该和你一起去 不过我不想去
I'd go with you, but I don't want to.
听着 阿尔
Listen, Al…
如果我再也见不到你
if I never see you again,
我希望你知道 我非常爱你
I want you to know that I love you very much.
还有 公寓里藏着
And also, uh, there's about 116 kilos of cocaine
116公斤的可卡因
buried somewhere in the apartment…
就在治失明的药旁边 祝你好运
right next to the cure for blindness. Good luck.
你想嗨一把吗？
You wanna get fucked up?
把她放在那
Put her down over here.
撕掉
Go on then.
谢了 没种的 我指你
Thanks, dickless. And I mean you.
哇 你话也很多嘛 你和韦德都这样
Wow. You're a talker too. You and Wade.
我一直想告诉你们这帮混蛋
I've been trying to tell you assholes,
你们抓错人了
you've got the wrong girl.
我的前男友已经死了
My old boyfriend, he's dead.
是吗 我也这么认为 但他总是回来
See, I thought that too. But he keeps on coming back.
跟只蟑螂似的
Like a cockroach…
不过比蟑螂更丑
but uglier.
我虽然感觉不到 但他能感受到
Now, I may not feel, but he does.
我们来看看 你命悬一线的时候 他会怎么做
Let's see how he fights with your head on the block.
《异形3》里的蕾普利
Ripley, from Alien 3!
滚你的 你够老了
Fuck, you're old.
这是假笑 掩饰着我的痛苦
Fake laugh. Hiding real pain.
去找那个银色大傻蛋去
Go get Silver Balls.
你俩要去觅食吗？早起的鸟儿有虫吃？
You guys going for a bite? Early bird special?
日落前吃晚饭或者存钱
Oh, like there's something wrong
好像还有什么不对一样
with eating before sundown or saving money.
不扯这个 知道你们放走的那个坏人吗？
No, you know that bad guy that you let go?
他手上有我的妹子
He's got my girl.
你们要帮我把她救回来
You're gonna help me get her back.
韦德 是你吗？
Wade, is that you?
对 是我 死侍
Yeah, it's me, Deadpool,
我这有个你不能拒绝的请求
and I got an offer that you can't refuse.
我就在外面等着 行吗？
I'm gonna wait out here, okay?
这房子真大啊
It's a big house.
奇怪我只看见你俩住这
It's funny that I only ever see two of you.
就好像这电影制作公司 没钱再打造一个X战警
It's almost like the studio couldn't afford another X-Man.
所以 在我看来
And that is why, in my opinion…
《天茧》这部电影完全就是黄片
the movie Cocoon is pure pornography.
这个闪闪发光的人是谁带来的？
Who brought this twinkly man?
闪闪发光 但也致命得很
Twinkly, but deadly.
后面这位长着合金蛋蛋的朋友
My chrome-penised friend back there
答应了要帮我个忙
has agreed to do me this solid.
作为条件 我答应他
In exchange, I said that I would
会考虑加入他的男子乐队
consider joining his boy band.
不是男子乐队
It's not boy band.
当然不是
Sure it's not.
那 有希望把吉塔赢回来吗？
So, any luck winning Gita back?
我试着紧握住 侍先生
I tried to hold on tight, Mr. Pool…
但是班都比我要狡猾得多 也帅得多
but Bandhu is more craftier and handsomer than me.
嗯 我觉得你就可爱得很
Well, I think you're pretty darn cute.
- 多芬德？- 嗯？
- Dopinder. - Hmm?
什么在叫？
What was that?
班都在后备箱里
That was Bandhu in the trunk.
班什么？
Ban who?
我的情敌班都 他被绑在后备箱里
My romantic rival Bandhu. He's tied up in the trunk.
我是照你说的做的 死侍
I'm doing as you said, DP.
我准备像做烧烤鱼一样把他的内脏都剔了
I plan to gut him like a tandoori fish,
然后把他的尸体放到吉塔家的台阶上
then dump his carcass on Gita's doorstep.
我没叫他这么做
I did not tell him to do that.
绝对没有 你理解错了
Absolutely not. It got lost in translation.
多芬德 你不可能赢回吉塔的心了
Dopinder, this is no way to win Gita's heart back!
我真为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
小心 安全地把班都放下来
Drop Bandhu off, safe and gentle-like.
杀了他
Kill him.
然后再赢回吉塔
And then, win Gita back…
用最土的办法啊 利用你作为男人的吸引力
the old fashioned way: with your boyish charm.
绑了她
Kidnap her.
他死定了
He's super dead.
我才要来个爽快的击掌吧？
I presume a crisp high five?
对你？要来俩
For you? 10.
好嘞 两位 我们出去干大事吧
Okay, guys, let's get out there and make a difference.
你知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
把他们全放倒 侍兄
Knock 'em dead, Pool Boy!
是时候好好揍一顿人了
Time to make the chimi-fuckin'-changas.
一个让你毁容的人
Not often a dude ruins your face…
同时还摧毁了你的理智 掳走了你未来宝宝的妈妈
skull-stomps your sanity, grabs your future baby mama…
他参与了你人生最糟糕五瞬间中的四个 这可真是罕见
and personally sees to four of your five shittiest moments.
这么说吧 我有种圣诞节要来了的感觉
Let's just say it's beginning to look a lot like Christmas.
嘿
Hey.
你的弹药包呢？
Where's your duffle bag?
（死侍先生 来电）
班都？
Bandhu?
请留言 祝你今天愉快
Leave a message and have a happy day.
我去
God damn it!
要用老套的办法来解决了
I'm gonna do this the old fashioned way…
用两把剑 和我的全力
with two swords and maximum effort.
音乐开始
Cue the music.
韦德威尔逊
Wade Wilson!
我叫什么？
What's my name?
我给你拼出来
Oh, I'mma fuckin' spell it out for ya.
开打吧
Go get some.
超级英雄式降落
Superhero landing.
她要来个超级英雄式降落
She's gonna do a superhero landing.
等着看吧
Wait for it.
超级英雄式降落
Superhero landing!
你的膝盖真的要承受好大压力啊
You know, that's really hard on your knees.
一点都不实用 他们都能这么做
Totally impractical. They all do it.
你是个挺可爱的女人 不过我要把自己留给弗朗西斯
You're a lovely lady, but I'm saving myself for Francis.
所以我才带他来
That's why I brought him.
我不想打女人 所以请你…
I prefer not to hit a woman, so please…
我是说 所以我才带她来？
I mean, that's why I brought her?
噢 不 快发完你的推特 这不是… 那是…
Oh, no, finish your tweet. It's not… That's…
等我们一会儿啊
Just give us a second. Yeah.
对 加个话题
There you go. Hashtag it.
搞定她 小老虎
Go get her, tiger.
真为那个要强上了她的兄弟感到惋惜
Oh, I so pity the dude who pressures her into prom sex.
好啊 开火
All right, then. Fire!
赶紧了结了那个婊子
Finish fucking her the fuck up!
请注意用语
Language, please.
快上
Suck a cock.
别看我 孩子
Look away, child.
别看我
Look away!
等等
Wait!
停火
Cease fire!
小伙伴们 嘿 嘿
Fellas! Hey! Hey!
你们只为那个屁都不如的混球干活儿
You only work for that shit-spackled muppet fart.
所以 我给你们一个机会
So, I'mma give you a chance
让你们放下武器
for y'all to lay down your firearms…
我会用近乎温柔的方式优待你们
in exchange for preferential, bordering on gentle…
说不定甚至还会带着爱意
possibly even lover-like treatment.
好啊
Fine.
突击
Commando!
吃我的蛋
Teabag!
鲍勃？
Bob?
韦德？
Wade?
噢 我的天 我好久没见过你了 自从…
Oh, my God, I haven't seen you since…
- 杰克逊维尔 星期五餐厅 - 星期五餐厅之后
- Jacksonville. Fridays. - Since TGI Fridays.
我勒个去
Well, what the hell!
天呐 来吧 你
God, come here, you.
孩子怎么样？还好吗？
How are the kids? Good?
盖尔是不是还爱吃金枪鱼砂锅？
And Gail, she still fixing that tuna casserole?
真不错 不过腰围会有麻烦
So good. But bad for the waistline,
你知道我在说什么吧
if you know what I'm talking about.
你的… 左边 你还是挺漂亮的
Your… On the left. You are beautiful woman.
真贴心
That is so sweet.
谢谢
Thanks.
（弗朗西斯）
他也会给你写便条吗？
Does he write you notes too?
他可真浪漫
He's such a romantic.
别担心 宝贝 我来了
Don't worry, baby. I'm comin'.
开火
Fire!
嘿
Hey!
爬上去
Climb on!
妈的…
Motherfucking…
那个畜生应该穿他那条红棕色的裤子
Motherfucker should have worn his brown pants.
你说得对 美女
You were right, beautiful.
我穿红色很合适
Red really is my color.
韦德？
Wade?
别担心 宝贝
Don't worry, baby…
我要把你从这个鬼盒子里救出来
I'mma get you out of that shit-box.
还有什么更好的办法 能把你逼疯？
What better way to crawl back inside that head of yours?
噢 你从来没逼疯过我
Oh, you never left.
但我被你逼疯了 混蛋
But you did, asshole!
深呼吸 亲爱的
Ah, deep breath, darling.
噢 等等
Oh, wait.
说错了话
Wrong choice of words.
我希望你的痛感神经已经全死光了
I hope they blocked pain to your every last nerve.
因为我要好好检查检查
'Cause I'mma go lookin'!
听说你的身体部分能自己长回来 韦德
I hear you grow back body parts now, Wade.
等我了结了你
When I'm finished…
你得被拼起来才能恢复了
parts will have to grow back you.
说得好
Good one.
是啊 说得确实不错
Yep, that was a good one.
开跳吧
Let's dance.
跳的意思是
And by dance, I mean…
开杀吧
let's try to kill each other.
行啊 用拳头
Fine. Fists.
上周六被人用拳头爆菊了吧
Oh, sounds like your last Saturday night.
混蛋
Asshole!
坚持住 宝贝
Hang in there, baby!
- 韦德 - 抓住你了
- Wade! - I gotcha!
我有个办法 你是不会喜欢的
I got a plan. You're not gonna like it.
该死 该死 该死
Shit! Shit! Shit!
别担心 我完全能处理好
Don't worry. I'm totally on top of this.
该死
Ah! Damn it!
全力出击
Maximum effort!
谢谢
Thanks.
慢慢出来
Just take it slow.
噢 我的天 真是…
Oh, my God! That was so…
无法用语言形容
There are no words!
我跟你去把我这张脸整好
Me and you are headed to fix this butterface.
什么？
What?
你个蠢到家的
You stupid fucking idiot.
你还真以为有办法能治好… 那个？
Did you really think there was a cure… for that?
什么？
What?
你听明白了
You heard me.
不
No.
No!
所以 你是说…
So, you mean to say…
折腾这么一顿 结果你治不好我？
after all this, you can't fix me?
你说出来显得更蠢了
It sounds even stupider when you say it.
我留你这条小命 只是为了治好我的脸
Like the kind of stupid who admits
结果这个理由也没了 我有你蠢？
he can't do the one thing I'm keeping him alive for?
有什么遗言？
Any last words?
我叫什么？
What's my name?
谁在乎这个？
Who fucking cares?
韦德
Wade!
四五个瞬间
Four or five moments.
什么意思？
I'm sorry?
只需要四五个瞬间
Four or five moments, that's all it takes.
怎样？
To?
成为一名英雄
Be a hero.
人人都以为英雄是项全职工作
Everyone thinks it's a full-time job.
醒来就是英雄 刷牙时也是英雄
Wake up a hero, brush your teeth a hero,
上班时还是英雄
go to work a hero.
并非如此
Not true.
一生中只有四五个瞬间
Over a lifetime, there are only four or five moments
是真正重要的
that really matter.
就是你做选择的瞬间
Moments when you're offered a choice.
做出牺牲 战胜缺点
To make a sacrifice, conquer a flaw,
拯救朋友
save a friend…
放过对手
spare an enemy.
在这些瞬间
In these moments…
其余一切都不重要了
everything else falls away.
世人如何看待我们
The way the world sees us.
我们…
The way we…
为什么开枪？
Why?
你太啰嗦了
You were droning on.
当然 我可能会一直 顶着这张发糕一样的脸
Sure, I may be stuck looking like pepperoni flatbread…
但起码这混蛋是活不过来了
but at least fuckface won't heal from that.
如果作为超级英雄
If wearing superhero tights…
就等于放过危险的疯子
means sparing psychopaths…
那或许我并不应该成为超级英雄
then maybe I wasn't meant to wear 'em.
又不是每个人都跟你一样 高尚得跟个圣父似的
Not everyone monitors a hall like you.
你保证…
Just promise…
行 行 接下来四个瞬间
Yeah, yeah, I'll be on the lookout
我会注意的
for the next four moments.
噢 该死
Oh, shit.
不好意思 我是个男孩
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'm just a boy,
我要站在一个女孩面前
about to stand in front of a girl…
告诉她…
and tell her…
我他妈要告诉她什么？
What the fuck am I gonna tell her?
嗯 你最好自己想清楚
Well, hmm, you better figure it out.
我甚至没办法告诉你…
I can't even tell you…
我该 还是该
I deserved that. That, too.
不不不 裆还是算了吧
No, no, no, maybe not the nethers.
你说啊
Start talking!
对不起
I'm sorry.
真的对不起
I'm so sorry.
什么都对不起 对不起我离开了
For everything, I'm sorry for leaving…
对不起我没有早点出来解决
I'm sorry for not cowboying up sooner.
这几年很艰难
It's been rough couple of years.
艰难？
Rough?
我住在贩毒的房子里
I live in a crackhouse.
和一家12口人同住
With a family of 12.
每晚我们都要挤着取暖
Every night we spoon for warmth.
大家都争着要靠着诺埃尔 她是最胖的
Everybody fights for Noelle. She's the fattest.
我们什么都是共享的
There's nothing that we don't share.
空间 牙线 甚至安全套
Floor space, dental floss, even condoms.
所以你还能住在房子里
So, you live in a house.
我应该早点来找你的
I should have come and found you sooner.
但是 宝贝 面具下的这个人
But, baby, the guy under this mask,
已经不是你记忆中的样子了
he ain't the same one that you remember.
你是说这副面具？
You mean this mask?
还有这副
And this one.
防止那副掉了
In case the other fell off.
好吧 就…
All right. Yeah, just… Ow.
和急救绷带差不多 就…
Like a Band-Aid, just give it a…
痛死我了
Owdie 5, 000.
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait…
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
我确定
I'm sure.
哇
Wow.
是的
Yeah.
嘿
Hey.
经过短暂的适应期
After a brief adjustment period…
再喝一大堆酒
and a bunch of drinks…
这张脸…
it's a face…
我很愿意坐上去
I'd be happy to sit on.
这套战服下的我 也不是以前的那个我了
I'm not the same underneath this suit, either.
不是了
No.
老二超级大
Super-penis.
拜托 韦德 注意用语
Come on, Wade. Language.
这有小孩子呢
Young one is present.
你们还在这干嘛？
What are you still doing?
一边去 去找点事做
Get out of here. Go make yourself useful!
你 用你这大块头去帮帮谁啊
You, go be a really big brother to someone.
让野兽别在我的草坪上拉屎了
Tell Beast to stop shitting on my lawn.
还有你 小鸡仔
And you, chicken noodle…
无人可以取代你
Nothing compares to you.
西尼德奥康娜1990年唱的歌 不好意思
Sinéad O'Connor, 1990. Sorry.
没关系 你很酷
That's all right. You're cool.
说啥玩意儿？
What in the ass?
不是在骂我啊 我真为你骄傲
That was not mean. I'm proud of you!
我们会把你打造成一个X战警的 韦德
We will make an X-Man of you yet, Wade.
有那么一会儿
For a second there,
我觉得我们就像三个迷你机器狮
it felt like we were three mini-lion robots…
在一起组合成了一个超级机器人
coming together to form one super robot.
好蠢的话
There's a stupid.
是啊
Yeah.
现在 我一直在等这一刻
And now, for the moment I've all been waiting for.
过来
Come here.
威猛乐队 我们说好的
Wham! As promised.
看到没？
See?
并不需要成为超级英雄才追到妹子
You don't need to be a superhero to get the girl.
对的人会让你变成超级英雄
The right girl will bring out the hero in you.
现在 结局我们要拉个广角镜头 镜头往后拉出
Now, let's finish this epic wide shot. Pull out.
对 继续 不错
There we go, that looks nice.
这会是今晚唯一一个会「拉出」的东西
That's gonna be about the only thing that's pulling out tonight.
圆满结局 谁不喜欢呢？
Who doesn't love a happy ending, huh?
下次见
'Til next time, this is
现在由这位可怜又友好的邻居 为大家演唱
your friendly neighborhood pool guy singin'…
∮ 我终将不再跳舞 ∮
∮ I'm never gonna dance again ∮
∮ 无法像你我从前那样跳舞 ∮
∮ The way I danced with you ∮
∮ 不能与你重温舞步 ∮
∮ The way without you ∮
∮ 今晚的音乐看似过于喧嚣 ∮
∮ Tonight the music seems so loud ∮
∮ 但愿我们能避开人群 ∮
∮ I wish that we could lose this crowd ∮
∮ 也许这样会比较好 ∮
∮ Maybe it's better this way ∮
∮ 我们可以用真心话来伤害彼此 ∮
∮ We'd hurt each other with the things we want to say ∮
∮ 我们本该是令人羡慕的一对 ∮
∮ We could have been so good together ∮
∮ 我们本该让这曲共舞永无终结 ∮
∮ We could have lived this dance forever ∮
∮ 但现在也没人原意与我共舞 ∮
∮ But now who's gonna dance with me ∮
∮ 留下来好吗 ∮
∮ Please stay ∮
∮ 我再也不跳舞了 ∮
∮ I'm never gonna dance again ∮
∮ 充满罪恶的双脚抓不住节奏 ∮
∮ Guilty feet have got no rhythm ∮
∮ 虽然伪装很容易 ∮
∮ Though it's easy to pretend ∮
∮ 但我知道你也并非傻瓜 ∮
∮ I know you're not a fool ∮
∮ 早知不该欺骗朋友 ∮
∮ I should have known better than to cheat a friend ∮
∮ 也浪费了被赐予的大好机会 ∮
∮ And waste a chance that I'd been given ∮
∮ 所以我不再跳舞了 ∮
∮ So I'm never gonna dance again ∮
∮ 不能再如往日一般与你共舞 ∮
∮ The way I danced with you ∮
∮ 如今 你已离我而去 ∮
∮ Now that you're gone ∮
∮ 我犯下的错真的如此深重吗 ∮
∮ I did so wrong So wrong ∮
∮ 令你离我而去 只留下我孤身一人 ∮
∮ that you had to leave me alone ∮
《死侍》
还在呢？
You're still here?
结束了 回家去吧
It's over. Go home.
你们在等着《死侍2》的预告片啊
Oh, you're expecting a teaser for Deadpool 2.
好吧 我们可没那个钱
Well, we don't have that kind of money.
你们还想看什么？以为能看到萨缪尔杰克逊呢？
What are you expecting? Sam Jackson to show up?
还带着个眼罩 穿着件拉风的皮衣？
With an eye patch and a saucy little leather number?
快走 快走
Go. Go.
不过我能告诉你们一件事 是个小秘密哦
But I can tell you one thing, and it's a bit of a secret.
下一部里会有电索
For the sequel, we're gonna have Cable.
这角色了不起 有条机械左臂 还能时空旅行
Amazing character. Bionic arm, time travel.
我们还不知道谁来演
We have no idea who we're gonna cast yet,
谁都有可能
but it could be anybody.
只要是个平头的大块头
Just need a big guy with a flat top.
可能是梅尔吉布森 道夫龙格尔
Could be Mel Gibson, Dolph Lundgren…
凯拉奈特莉 她戏路广着呢 谁知道呢
Keira Knightley. She's got range. Who knows.
不管怎样 大秘密哟
Anyway, big secret. Shh…
别把垃圾留在这 弄得到处都是
Oh, and don't leave your garbage all lying around.
这种行为完全不能忍
It's a total dick move.
走吧
Go.